puma.de 2018-01-20

# Sites-EU-Site

## **PUMA Privacy Policy**

The PUMA Europe GmbH (hereinafter also referred to as "PUMA", "we" or "us") is responsible for the processing of your personal data that we receive or gather from you in connection with the use of our service on or via our European websites, or in connection with the use of other PUMA applications (e.g. on mobile devices), according to the German Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG).

**Contact data**

PUMA Europe GmbH  
PUMA Way 1  
91074 Herzogenaurach  
Germany

**E-Mail:**[service@puma.com](mailto:service@puma.com)

### **1\. Collecting Personal Data**

We use our technology to gather the following information:

  * _Information that is collected automatically:_ As soon as you visit our websites, we collect and store certain information automatically. This information includes Internet protocol addresses (IP), the type and version of browser you are using, your operating system and platform, including the uniform resource locator (URL). Westorethisdata in a completelyanonymousway.
  * _Information that you provide us with:_ Personal data you share with us in the course of submitting an order remain completely confidential. This includes, for example, your contact data, including your name and surname, address, your birth date, e-mail address,telephone number as well as your payment information, including your bank details and credit card information, invoice address.
  * _Information from other sources:_ In order to deliver your future orders securely and safely, we obtain information on payment behaviour, such as from mail-order companies, credit bureaus or updates regarding ordering and delivery addresses of parcel delivery and transport companies.
  * _Location-based data:_ We offer location-based services such as "Find a store." If you use these services, we receive information about your actual location only if you expressly agree to it in advance (e.g. GPS signals), or information regarding your approximate location (e.g., cell ID).

### **2\. Using Your Data to Process Your Order**

We use the personal information that you provide us with as part of the order process, to deliver the goods, to arrange payment and to send you information about your order. We require the following data to do this: contact information including title, first name, last name, street address, postal code, city, country, email address, birth date (to make sure the customer is over the age of 16) and phone number (in case we have any questions about your order).

For the purpose of payment processing the necessary data is stored both on our server and on the servers of the companies we have authorized to handle payment processing.

### **3\. Using Your Data for Advertising Purposes**

**Newsletter and product offers by e-mail**

If you register for the PUMA newsletter, you will receive regular product recommendations/updates from us that we will send to your specified email address). We use your information in this regard for promotional purposes, and to provide you with information about our range of products. These offers might be based on your past orders. To send the newsletter, we use the so-called double opt-in process, i.e., we will not send you the newsletter unless you confirm our notification e-mail by clicking on a link to let us know that you want to activate the newsletter service.

**Advertising in the context of existing customer relationship**

We use personal data you have shared with us in the process of purchasing a product or service to inform you about similar products and services from our product range and to request your feedback after the sale of a product or service, both by using electronic communication.

**Usage**

The data that is required to send the newsletters is forwarded to the companies PUMA has commissioned for handling shipping and is therefore stored on servers in the United States and Great Britain. These partners in turn provide PUMA with information related to emails that have been sent to you and confirmation that they have been read, information regarding your computer and Internet access, operating system and platform, date and time of the visit to the site and the products you have viewed.

**Right to object**

If you do not wish to receive further advertisement from us, you can object to such use at any time, by clicking on the unsubscribe link included in each advertisement message, or by sending us a message (for contact details see section 11, below). 

### **4\. Passing Your Personal Data on to Third Parties**

We will not pass on your personal data to anyone not included in this data privacy statement. The only exception to this would be to serve legal obligations.

### **5\. Cookies**

This section contains information about our usage of cookies as well as user’s consent as to the usage of tracking and third-party cookies. 

_What are cookies?_

At various points on our website, we use "cookies." Cookies are small text files that the web browser stores on your hard drive. Cookies collect and store certain information which can be accessed by web servers.

_Cookies and personal data_

In general, no personal data is stored in the cookies that the PUMA Online Store uses. That way, none of the cookies can be attributed directly to you or anyone else without your prior consent. An identification number is assigned to a cookie when it is activated. So the cookie technology only supplies us with information of a user with a certain Cookie-ID (pseudonym). A combination of a Cookie-ID and personal data of the user (e.g. name, email address etc.) and thus a direct attribution of the information collected by or stored in the cookie to a certain user only takes place if the user has given his unambiguous prior consent.. For example, in order to facilitate secure online access so that you do not have to retype your user ID and password each time you visit the site, your user ID and password can be saved in cookies to make logging in to our website easier and faster.

_Types and purposes of cookies used by PUMA_

Necessary Cookies

We use cookies which are necessary to make navigating and visiting web sites user friendly. They enable our systems, for example, to set the right language or to save your basket between visits.

Tracking and third-party cookies

We also use tracking cookies to analyze visitor preferences (e.g. data regarding which pages a customer visited in our online store, which products were viewed, etc.), which enables us to tailor our website and improve our offer for you. For more details which of our statistic and marketing tools use such tracking cookies and what kind of data is tracked and stored with these cookies see below under sec. 6 ff. of this Privacy Policy.

Our website also uses third-party cookies for "re-targeting". We use these cookies to make our internet offers as appealing to you as possible. This technology allows internet users who are already interested in our store and our products to respond to the advertising on our partner websites. Cookie technology enables us to insert advertising on our partner pages.

**With the usage of our website you consent to our usage of these tracking and third-party cookies. If you don’t want that, please ensure that (these) cookies are disabled in your browser settings. You can also at any time withdraw your consent for the future by deleting existing cookies and setting up your browser preferences appropriate to prevent that new (kinds of) cookies are set. More information about how cookies can be prevented and deleted can be found in the section (“Prevention and deletion of cookies”) below.**

_Prevention and deletion of cookies_

You can prevent cookies from being stored on your hard drive by setting up the necessary settings in your browser. You can also delete cookies already stored on your computer at any time. For details on how to do this, please refer to your browser’s manual or your browser manufacturer's help function. There you will learn:

  * – how your browser can notify you when you receive a new cookie;
  * – how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, or
  * – how to disable cookies to keep them from being obtained and stored in general and
  * how to delete cookies.

And of course, you can delete cookies already stored on your computer at any time.

You can also turn off or delete similar functions, such as flash cookies, which browser add-ons use, by changing the browser add-on settings or via the website of the browser add-on manufacturer (e.g. the Adobe Flash Player site).

Of course, you can also view our website without cookies. However, this can lead to function restrictions on our site (for example, regarding using the shopping cart).

### **6\. Web Analysis**

To continuously improve and optimize our service, we use Adobe Systems Incorporated, Webtrekk GmbH and Mapp Digital US LLC tracking technologies to statistically evaluate our websites.

We use Adobe Analytics(Omniture), Webtrekk and Mapp services to collect statistical data on the use of our website. We use this data to improve the PUMA Online Shop, and to improve and optimize our offers on an ongoing basis, which makes visiting our website more exciting for you.

When visiting this site, your browser provides information that is collected and analyzed. This is done using cookie technology and pixels that are included on each site. The following data are collected: request (file name of the requested file), browser type/version, browser language, operating system, internal resolution of the browser, screen resolution, java script enabled, Java on/off cookies on/off, color depth, referring URL, IP address (will only be collected anonymously and deleted immediately after use), time of access, clicks, order values, shopping carts and form content that is rendered anonymous (for example, whether a phone number has been specified or not).

None of this data can ever be directly attributed to you. The data collected is used to create anonymous or pseudonymized user profiles, which are the basis for web stats. The data that Adobe Analytics, Webtrekk and Mapp cookies collect is not used to identify visitors to this website at any time, nor is it merged together with any personal data related to the bearer of the profile, unless the user gives its unambiguous prior consent.

Adobe Analytics, Webtrekk and Mapp data collection and storage can be revoked at any time and will remain that way for the future. Please go to the following links:  
_Adobe Analytics:_ <http://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html>  
_Webtrekk:_  [ http://www.webtrekk.com/en/index/dataprivacy.html](http://www.webtrekk.com/en/index/dataprivacy.html)

_Mapp:_  

Follow each of the above-mentioned links to set an opt-out cookie. This opt-out cookie remains valid for at least 5 years. Please note that when deleting all cookies on your computer, this opt-out cookie will also be deleted, so you have to reset the opt-out cookie if you want to continue to reject anonymous or pseudonymized data collection through Adobe Analytics, Webtrekk and/or Mapp.

The data privacy policies of Adobe Analytics, Webtrekk and Teradata Mapp can be found at these websites:

_Adobe Analytics:_ [ http://www.adobe.com/privacy/analytics.html](http://www.adobe.com/privacy/analytics.html)  
_Webtrekk:_ [ http://www.webtrekk.com/en/index/dataprivacy.html ](http://www.webtrekk.com/en/index/dataprivacy.html) _Mapp:_ flxone.com/privacy-platform  

_2\. Consent (“Opt-in”) for merging pseudonymized usage profiles in DMP with personal data from the CEP_

Herewith I agree that the usage data collected on our website with the help of cookies from the Mapp system as well as data from already existing (pseudonymized) usage profiles from this system (for more information see sec. 5 (“Cookies”) and 6 (“Web Analysis”) of our privacy policy) is merged with my user data, additional information regarding surf behavior on Puma’s sites and is used for advertising purposes such as behavioral targeting, specific marketing in the fields of sportswear, sports equipment and supporting sports merchandise. I acknowledge that I have the right to withdraw my consent at any time by opting out of our newsletter or sending an email to [info@puma.com]. Such a withdrawal of consent does not affect the lawfulness of data processing based on the consent before the withdrawal.

### **7\. Google Analytics**

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. In case of activation of the IP anonymization, Google will anonymize the last octet of the IP address for Member States of the European Union as well as for other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases, the full IP address is sent to and shortened by Google servers in the USA. On behalf of PUMA Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage to the website provider. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. 

Please note that on this website Google Analytics code has been supplemented by “gat._anonymizeIp();” to ensure the anonymized collection of IP addresses.

You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. However, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. Furthermore you can prevent Google’s collection and use of data (cookies and IP address) by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available under <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>

Further information concerning data privacy can be found at _https://www.google.de/intl/en/policies/_

Disable Google Analytics%E2%80%9D)

### **8\. The Facebook Like Button**

Our sites receive social plug-ins from the social network Facebook, which is operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA. The social plug-ins include the Facebook "Like" button, and the plug-ins are marked with a Facebook logo (thumbs-up icon) or are identified by the additional "Facebook social" plug-in.

When you access a website from our website that contains this type of plug-in, your browser establishes a direct connection with the Facebook servers and sends this data to Facebook. This is true regardless of whether you are a member of Facebook, whether you are logged in while visiting our site as a member of Facebook, or if you click the plug-in. If you are a Facebook member and are logged in at Facebook while on our website, Facebook will assign your visit to our site to your Facebook account, even if you do not click the social plug-in. But if you do click the plug-in, this information will be transmitted to your Facebook account and stored there. The nature and extent of information transmitted to Facebook data are beyond our control. Nor do we know in detail which of your data will be transmitted to Facebook, or for what purpose Facebook uses this data. This data includes your IP address, and Facebook's own information on the website you visited, the date and time of the visit and other browser-related information. If a visitor visits the PUMA website while also logged in on Facebook, their login ID will also be collected and processed, and Facebook will assign this visit to the visitor's Facebook account. You must log out of Facebook before visiting our website if you want to prevent the embedded Facebook social plug-in on our site from transmitting your data to your Facebook account. More information on Facebook can be found at this website: [http://www.facebook.com/help/social-plugins/ ](http://www.facebook.com/help/social-plugins/).

Refer to Facebook privacy policies for more information on the collection, storage and use of your personal data by Facebook, and the configuration options available to you to protect your personal information: [http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/ ](http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/).

### **9\. Twitter Plug-Ins**

Our pages contain plug-ins that are integrated with the short-message network Twitter Inc., 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA. The Twitter logo identifies the Twitter plug-ins (tweet button) on our site. Please visit this link for a tweet button overview: [http://dev.twitter.com/ ](http://dev.twitter.com/). When you visit our site, the plug-in makes a direct connection between your browser and the Twitter server. Twitter thereby obtains the information that you have visited our site using your IP address. If you click on the Twitter "tweet" button while you are logged into your Twitter account, you can link the content of our pages to your Twitter profile. This allows Twitter correlate your visit to our site with your user account. We would like to point out that we as provider of our sites have no knowledge of the contents of the transmitted data or their use through Twitter. For more information, please see Twitter's privacy policy at [http://twitter.com/privacy ](http://twitter.com/privacy)

If you do not want Twitter to assign your visit to our pages to your Twitter user account, please log out of your Twitter account first.

### **10\. Protecting Your Data**

We secure our website and other systems against loss, destruction, unauthorized access, modification or distribution of your data by unauthorized persons by implementing the appropriate technical and organizational measures. Furthermore, your personal data is transmitted to us in encrypted format. This applies to your order and when you log in as a customer. We use the SSL (Secure Socket Layer) coding system.

### **11\. Right to Information and Right to Object**

There is a right to information about your personal data that we store andthe right to rectification, blocking and deleting your stored personal data.

You have the right to object to the use or processing of your data at any time. You have the right to revoke any consent you have previously granted us regarding the use of your personal data.

If you wish to avail yourself of your right to information and/or the right to object to the use of your personal data, or any other questions about privacy, please send us an e-mail at: [service@puma.com](mailto:service@puma.com)

or contact us by regular overland post:

PUMA Online Shop  
Postfach 201101   
48092 Münster  
Germany

This Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service are revised and updated regularly. Updates to this Privacy Policy are released on our website. Amendments apply as soon as they are published on our website. We therefore recommend that you check this page regularly to see whether there are any updates you need to be aware of.
